Guide to the Stephen Henry Schneider Papers SC1053
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stephen Henry Schneider papers
1965-2014
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Schneider, Stephen Henry
SC1053
371.75 Linear Feet (300 boxes)
Personal and professional files of Stephen Henry Schneider (1945-2010), Melvin and Joan Lane Professor for Interdisciplinary Environmental Studies, Professor of Biological Sciences, Professor (by courtesy) of Civil and Environmental Engineering, and a Senior Fellow in the Woods Institute for the Environment at Stanford University.
Access to Collection
Apart from Series 1, Climatic Change Editorial records, the materials are open for research. Series 1 is restricted 40 years from date of creation. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of personal and professional files of Stephen Henry Schneider (1945-2010) arranged in fourteen series. The first series is Climatic Change Editorial Records. Dr. Schneider was founder and editor of Climatic Change, a journal is dedicated to the totality of the problem of climatic variability and change – its descriptions, causes, implications and interactions among these. Included in this series are original manuscripts (accepted and rejected), editiorial correspondence, and special issues.
The second series is Personal Material. This includes but is not limited to awards, personal and professional address books, and calendars.
The third series is Correspondence. There are three subseries in this series: Alphabetical, Chronological and Restricted. Restricted matrerials include correspondence of private affairs or information closed to research use.
The fourth series is Research and Subject Files. This series has three subseries: Proposals (by and to Dr. Schneider), Topics and Organizations.
The fifth series is Publications. This series three subseries: Books, Articles, and Websites. Books contains information on the processes for several books: Politics of Climate, Genesis Strategy, Laboratory Earth, and Primordial Bond. Articles contains folders for reprints and drafts. Websites includes Dr. Schneider's personal website, as well as climatechange.net.
The sixth series is Conferences, Meetings, and Professional Travel. Included in this series are materials documenting the Phytopathological Society, World Food Population Confrontation and Rising Tide Summit.
The seventh series is Intergrovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC). This includes editorials, reports, correspondence, memos and other materials.
The eighth series is Teaching and Professional Work. This includes course materials, materials concerning students, administrative files, and consulting files.
The ninth series is Works by Others. This includes any work that was published and/or done about Stephen Schneider but not work that he personally wrote or co-authored.
The tenth series is Print Media. This includes newspaper clippings, articles or research related information by or about Stephen Schneider.
The eleventh series is Photographs. This includes images either taken by Schneider, photos of Schneider, or photos belonging to or given to Schneider.
The twelfth series is Audiovisual materials. This includes audio and video recordings of Schneider or are relevant to his research or interests.
The thirteenth series is Computer Files. This includes various computer media, such as floppies, CD-ROMs, external hard drives, computer software, etc.
The fourteenth series is Miscellaneous. This contains files that do not easily fall into any of the other thirteen series.
Arrangement note
The materials are arranged in fourteen series: Series 1. Climatic Change Editorial Records; Series 2. Personal; Series 3. Correspondence; Series 4. Research and Subject Files; Series 5. Publications; Series 6. Conferences, Meetings, and Professional Travel; Series 7. Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC); Series 8. Teaching and Professional Work; Series 9. Works by Others; Series 10. Print Media; Series 11. Photographs; Series 12. Audiovisual Material; Series 13. Computer Files; Series 14. Miscellaneous.
Timeline
Timeline
1945 Born on February 11th and raised on Long Island
1966 Received his BS in Mechanical Engineering from Columbia University
1971 Co-author on a Science paper with S.I. Rasool, "Atmospheric Carbon Dioxide and Aerosols: Effects of Large Increases on Global Climate" Postdoctoral research associate with the Goodard Institute in Space Studies with NASA (1971-1972) Received his Ph.D. in Mechanical Engineering and Plasma Physics from Columbia University
1972 Moved to Boulder, Colorado Awarded a postdoctoral fellowship at the National Center for Atmospheric Research (NCAR)
1973 Became a member of the scientific staff of NCAR (1973-1996)
1975 Created the "Climate Change" Journal with NCAR; Editor-in-chief (1975-2010)
1976 Wrote The Genesis Strategy: Climate and Global Survival
1978 Married Cheryl K. Hatter
1979 Featured in US Magazine Article, "The Top 35 Up-and-Comers under 35"
1981 Part of the Scientific Division Directors in the Appointments Review Group (ARG) (1981-1982)
1984 Co-author with Randi Londer for Coevolution of Climate and Life Listed in the "100 Oustanding Young Scientists in America"
1985 Part of the Scientific Division Directors in the Appointments Review Group (ARG) (1981-1982)
1987 Consultant to the Under Secretary of Defense (1987-1988)
1988 Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) was founded - Schneider became an active member since it's founding Became a member of the Staff of the Defense Science Board Task Force on Atmospheric Obscuration with the Department of Defense
1989 Wrote Global Warming: Are We Entering the Greenhouse Century? Member of the AGU Macelwane Medal Subcommittee
1991 Awarded the American Association for the Advancement of Science/Westinghouse Award for Public Understanding of Science and Technology
1992 Entered academia part time Honored with a MacArthur Fellowship
1995 Founding Member of the Committee for Research on Global Environmental Change
1996 Joined Stanford University staff as a professor of climatalogy (1996-2010)
1997 Wrote Laboratory Earth: the Planetary Gamble We Can't Afford to Lose Wrote Implications of the "Greenhouse Effect" for the World Book Publishing Co. for their CD-ROM Encyclopedia
1998 Became a foreign member of the Academea Europea
1999 Made Chair of the AAAS’s Section on Atmospheric and Hydrospheric Sciences (1999–2001)
2000 Co-author of "Uncertainities in the IPCC Third Assessment Report: Recommendations to Lead Authors for More Consistent Assessement and Reporting"
2001 A member of the Core Writing Team for the IPCC Third Assessment Report (TAR)
2002 Co-Director of the Stanford Center for Environmental Science and Policy (CESP) (2002-2007) Elected to membership in the US National Academy of Sciences
2003 Co-won the National Conservation Achievement Award from the National Wildlife Federation with his wife, Terry Root Co-Director of E-IPER (2003-2005) Received the Edward T. Law Roe Award of the Society of Conservation Biology
2004 Co-author of the cross-cutting theme paper #4: "Assessing the Science to Address UNFCCC Article 2"
2005 Wrote The Patient from Hell; an account of his survival of mantle cell lymphoma (an aggressive cancer)
2006 Received the Banksia Foundation's International Environmental Award in Australia
2007 A member of the Core Writing Team for the IPCC Fourth Assessment Report (TAR) Received a collective Nobel Peace Prize with fellow IPCC authors
2008 Carl Moyer Award for Scientific Leadership & Technical Leadership Coaliation for Clean Air Received a Fellow of the Institute of Green Professionals
2010 Awarded an honorary fellowship at the California Academy of Sciences Passed away in London, England on July 19th after suffering a pulmonary embolism while returning from a scientific meeting in Käringön, Sweden.
Biographical/Historical note
Dr. Stephen H. Schneider (1945-2010) was the Melvin and Joan Lane Professor for Interdisciplinary Environmental Studies, Professor of Biological Sciences, Professor (by courtesy) of Civil and Environmental Engineering, and a Senior Fellow in the Woods Institute for the Environment at Stanford University. Dr. Schneider received his Ph.D. in Mechanical Engineering and Plasma Physics from Columbia University in 1971. He studied the role of greenhouse gases and suspended particulate material on climate as a postdoctoral fellow at NASA's Goddard Institute for Space Studies. He was awarded a postdoctoral fellowship at the National Center for Atmospheric Research in 1972 and was a member of the scientific staff of NCAR from 1973-1996, where he co-founded the Climate Project.
Internationally recognized for research, policy analysis and outreach in climate change, Dr. Schneider focused on climate change science, integrated assessment of ecological and economic impacts of human-induced climate change, and identifying viable climate policies and technological solutions. He consulted with federal agencies and/or White House staff in the Nixon, Carter, Reagan, G.H.W. Bush, Clinton and G.W. Bush administrations.
Actively involved with the IPCC (Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change), an initiative of the United Nations Environment Program and the World Meteorological Organization since its origin in 1988, Dr. Schneider was co-author of "Uncertainties in the IPCC Third Assessment Report: Recommendations to Lead Authors for More Consistent Assessment and Reporting"in 2000 and the cross-cutting theme paper #4: "Assessing the Science to Address UNFCCC Article 2" in 2004. He has been a contributor to all four IPCC Assessment Reports and is currently a Coordinating Lead Author of Working Group II Chapter 19, "Assessing Key Vulnerabilities and the Risk from Climate Change." For the 2001 IPCC Third Assessment Report (TAR) and the 2007 Fourth Assessment Report (AR4), Dr. Schneider has also been a member of the Core Writing Team for each of the Synthesis Reports, which integrate the contributions of Working Groups I, II and III. The 2007 IPCC Fourth Assessment Report will be used by governments world-wide as the most up-to-date, credible document regarding climate change science, impacts, adaptation, vulnerability, and mitigation until 2012. After decades of work, Dr. Schneider, along with four generations of IPCC authors, received a collective Nobel Peace Prize in 2007.
In 1991, Dr. Schneider was awarded the American Association for the Advancement of Science/ Westinghouse Award for Public Understanding of Science and Technology for furthering public understanding of environmental science and its implications for public policy. In 1992, he was honored with a MacArthur Fellowship for his ability to integrate and interpret the results of global climate research through public lectures, classroom teaching, environmental assessment committees, media appearances, Congressional testimony and research collaboration with colleagues. In 1998, Dr. Schneider became a foreign member of the Academea Europaea, Earth & Cosmic Sciences Section. He was elected to membership in the US National Academy of Sciences in 2002. Dr. Schneider received the Edward T. Law Roe Award of the Society of Conservation Biology in 2003. He and his spouse-collaborator, Terry Root, jointly received the 2003 National Conservation Achievement Award from the National Wildlife Federation and the Banksia Foundation’s 2006 International Environmental Award in Australia.
Dr. Schneider was Founder and Editor of the interdisciplinary journal, Climatic Change, Editor-in-Chief of the Encyclopedia of Climate and Weather and author of The Genesis Strategy: Climate and Global Survival; Global Warming: Are We Entering the Greenhouse Century?, and The Coevolution of Climate and Life and Laboratory Earth: The Planetary Gamble We can't Afford to Lose. In addition, he has authored or co-authored over 400 scientific papers, proceedings, legislative testimonies, edited books and book chapters, and over 200 book reviews, editorials and other pieces for popular media.
Dr. Schneider taught undergraduate and graduate courses in Earth Systems, Civil Engineering, Biological Sciences, the Senior Honors Seminar in Environmental Science, Technology and Policy, and the doctoral program, The Interdisciplinary Graduate Program in Environment and Resources (IPER). He served as Co-Director of the Stanford Center for Environmental Science and Policy (CESP) from 2002 to 2007 and Co-Director of IPER, from 2003 to 2005.
Dr. Schneider actively counseled policy makers about the importance of using risk management strategies in climate-policy decision making, given the uncertainties in future projections of global climate change and related impacts. In addition to continuing to serve as advisor to decision-makers, he consulted with corporate executives and other stakeholders in industry and the nonprofit sectors regarding possible climate-related events and was actively engaged in improving public understanding of science and the environment through extensive media communication and public outreach.
Dr. Schneider was a survivor of an aggressive cancer, mantle cell lymphoma. He documented his struggle to conquer the condition, including applying his own knowledge of science to design his own treatment regime, in a self-published 2005 book, The Patient from Hell. He died unexpectedly on July 19, 2010 after suffering a pulmonary embolism while returning from a scientific meeting in Käringön, Sweden.
Greenhouse effect, Atmospheric.; Greenhouse effect, Atmospheric.; Nature -- Effect of human beings on; Nature -- Effect of human beings on; Climatic changes -- Government policy -- International cooperation.; Climatic changes -- Government policy -- International cooperation.; Human ecology.; Human ecology.; Climatic changes.; Climatic changes.; Global environmental change.; Global environmental change.; Global temperature changes.; Global temperature changes.; Schneider, Stephen Henry; Schneider, Stephen Henry; Root, Terry; Schneider, Stephen Henry; Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change; Root, Terry; Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change
- Climatic Change Editorial Records, 1977-2010; Series 1; 105.5 Linear Feet; (71 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Dr. Schneider was founder and editor of Climatic Change. The journal is dedicated to the totality of the problem of climatic variability and change – its descriptions, causes, implications and interactions among these. The purpose of the journal is to provide a means of exchange between those working on problems related to climatic variations but in different disciplines. Interdisciplinary researchers or those in any discipline, be it meteorology, anthropology, agricultural science, astronomy, biology, chemistry, physics, geography, policy analysis, economics, engineering, geology, ecology, or history of climate, are invited to submit articles, provided the articles are of interdisciplinary interest. This means that authors have an opportunity to communicate the essence of their studies to people in other climate related disciplines and to interested laypersons, as well as to report on research in which the originality is in the combinations of (not necessarily original) work from several disciplines. The journal also includes vigorous editorial and book review sections.
  Access to Collection
  Restricted 40 years from date of creation.
  - 34:3-4, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 1-16)
  - 44:1-2, 2000 Jan (Box 1, Folder 17-24)
  - 44:4-45:2, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 1-18)
  - 45:3-4, 2000 Jun (Box 2, Folder 19-28)
  - 45:3-4, 2000 Jun (Box 3, Folder 1-4)
  - 46:1-2, 2000 Jul (Box 3, Folder 5-10)
  - 46:4, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 11-14)
  - 46:4, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
  - 47:1-2, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 5-15)
  - 47:3-4, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 16-19)
  - 47:3-4, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 1-6)
  - 48:2-3, 2001 Feb (Box 5, Folder 7-15)
  - 48:2-3, 2001 Feb (Box 6, Folder 1-5)
  - 48:4, 2001 Mar (Box 6, Folder 6-13)
  - 49:1-2, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 14-17)
  - 49:1-2, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 1-9)
  - 49:4, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 10-15)
  - 49:4, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 1-9)
  - 50:1-2, 2001 July (Box 8, Folder 10-18)
  - 50:1-2, 2001 Jul (Box 9, Folder 1-10)
  - 50:3-4, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 11-16)
  - 50:3-4, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 1-8)
  - 51:2; 52:3, 2001 Nov, 2002 Feb (Box 10, Folder 9-17)
  - 51:2; 52:3, 2001 Nov, 2002 Feb (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
  - 52:1-2, 2002 Jan (Box 11, Folder 3-14)
  - 52:4; 53:4, 2002 Mar, 2002 Jun (Box 11, Folder 15-16)
  - 52:4; 53:4, 2002 Mar, 2002 Jun (Box 12, Folder 1-14)
  - 54:1-3, 2002 Jul-Aug (Box 12, Folder 15-21)
  - 54:1-3, 2002 Jul-Aug (Box 13, Folder 1-12)
  - 55:3-4, 2002 Sep-Nov (Box 13, Folder 13-20)
  - 55:3-4, 2002 Sep-Nov (Box 14, Folder 1-6)
  - 55:4; 56:3, 2002 Dec, 2003 Feb (Box 14, Folder 7-16)
  - 55:4; 56:3, 2002 Dec, 2003 Feb (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
  - 57:1-2, 2003 Mar (Box 15, Folder 3-15)
  - 57:3; 58:1-2, 2004 Apr, 2003 May (Box 16, Folder 1-17)
  - 58:3; 59:3; 60:3, 2003 Jun, 2003 Aug, 2003 Oct (Box 17, Folder 1-18)
  - 61:1-2, 2003 Nov (Box 17, Folder 19-20)
  - 61:1-2, 2003 Nov (Box 18, Folder 1-10)
  - 61:3, 2003 Dec (Box 18, Folder 11-15)
  - 63:1-2, 2004 Mar (Box 19, Folder 1-8)
  - 63:3, 2004 Apr (Box 19, Folder 9-14)
  - 64:3, 2004 (Box 20, Folder 1-5)
  - 65:1-2, 2004 (Box 20, Folder 6-13)
  - 66:1-2, 2004 (Box 21, Folder 1-13)
  - 67:1, 2004 (Box 21, Folder 14-17)
  - 67:1, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 1-8)
  - 68:1-2, 2005 Jan (Box 22, Folder 9-16)
  - 68:1-2, 2005 Jan (Box 23, Folder 1-5)
  - 70:3, 2005 Jun (Box 23, Folder 6-9)
  - 71:1-2, 2005 Jul (Box 23, Folder 10-13)
  - 71:1-2, 2005 Jul (Box 24, Folder 1-5)
  - 72:1-2, 2005 Sep (Box 24, Folder 6-13)
  - 72:1-2, 2005 Sep (Box 25, Folder 1-3)
  - 72:1-3; 72:3, 2005 Aug, 2005 Oct (Box 25, Folder 4-14)
  - 73:3, 2005 Dec (Box 26, Folder 1-8)
  - 74:1-3, 2006 Jan (Box 26, Folder 9-15)
  - 74:1-3, 2006 Jan (Box 27, Folder 1-9)
  - 74:4, 2006 Feb (Box 27, Folder 10-15)
  - 74:4, 2006 Feb (Box 28, Folder 1-5)
  - 75:1-4, 2006 Mar-Apr (Box 28, Folder 6-18)
  - 75:1-4, 2006 Mar-Apr (Box 29, Folder 1-5)
  - 76:3-4, 2006 Jun (Box 29, Folder 6-17)
  - 77:3-4, 2006 Aug (Box 29, Folder 18-20)
  - 77:3-4, 2006 Aug (Box 30, Folder 1-9)
  - 78:3-4, 2006 Oct (Box 30, Folder 10-16)
  - 78:3-4, 2006 Oct (Box 31, Folder 1-5)
  - 79:3-4, 2006 Dec (Box 31, Folder 6-15)
  - 79:3-4, 2006 Dec (Box 32, Folder 1-4)
  - 80:3-4, 2007 Feb (Box 32, Folder 5-16)
  - 81:2, 2007 Mar (Box 33, Folder 1-4)
  - 81:3-4, 2007 Apr (Box 33, Folder 5-17)
  - 82:1-2, 2007 May (Box 34, Folder 1-12)
  - 82:3-4, 2007 Jun (Box 34, Folder 13-17)
  - 82:3-4, 2007 Jun (Box 35, Folder 1-5)
  - 83:3-4 (Box 35, Folder 6-15)
  - 83:3-4 (Box 36, Folder 1-2)
  - 84:1-2 (Box 36, Folder 3-8)
  - 84:3-4 (Box 36, Folder 9-15)
  - 84:3-4 (Box 37, Folder 1-4)
  - Special issue: Does climate policy promote development? (Michaelowa), 2007 (Box 37, Folder 5-14)
  - Special issue: Geoengineering (Marland), 1995 (Box 37, Folder 15-23)
  - Special issue: PRUDENCE project (Christianson), 2007 (Box 38)
  - Special issue: Climate and water (Kabat) (Box 39, Folder 1-25)
  - Special issue: Soil-carbon sequestration (Rosenberg), 2000 (Box 39, Folder 26-28)
  - Special issue: Soil-carbon sequestration (Rosenberg), 2000 (Box 40, Folder 1-4)
  - Special issue: Economy, politics, and institutions (Sohngen), 2000 (Box 40, Folder 5-14)
  - Special issue: Forestry (Stocks), 2002 (Box 40, Folder 15-20)
  - Special issue: Forestry (Stocks), 2002 (Box 41, Folder 1-12)
  - Special issue: Agriculture and forestry (Salinger), 2002 (Box 41, Folder 13-22)
  - Special issue: Agriculture and forestry (Salinger), 2002 (Box 42, Folder 1-7)
  - Special issue: Forest gap models (Bugmann) (Box 42, Folder 8-18)
  - Special issue: Tropical deforestation (Myers), 1991 (Box 43, Folder 1-25)
  - Special issue: Climate change impact for coterminous United States (Rosenberg), 2003 (Box 43, Folder 26-32)
  - Special issue: Climate change impact for coterminous United States (Rosenberg), 2003 (Box 44, Folder 1-4)
  - Special issue: Soil-carbon sequestration (Dumanski and Lai) (Box 44, Folder 5-14)
  - Special issue: Mititation of greenhouse gas emissions by the agricultural sector (Cole), 1998 (Box 44, Folder 15-22)
  - Special issue: Carbon sinks (Canadell (Box 45, Folder 1-19)
  - Special issue (Diaz), 2003 (Box 45, Folder 20-21)
  - Special issue (Diaz), 2003 (Box 46, Folder 1-13)
  - Special issue: Little Ice Age (Ogilvie) (Box 46, Folder 14-20)
  - Special issue: Little Ice Age (Ogilvie) (Box 47, Folder 1-8)
  - Special issue: Climatic variability (Mearns) (Box 47, Folder 9-18)
  - Special issue: Adaptability to climate change (Kane) (Box 48, Folder 1-15)
  - Special issue: Tropical rainforests (Box 48, Folder 16-22)
  - Special issue: Tropical rainforests (Box 49, Folder 1-5)
  - Special issue: ICLIPS (Toth) (Box 49, Folder 6-16)
  - Special issue: Climatic variability, a European perspective (Grosjean) (Box 49, Folder 17-21)
  - Special issue: Climatic variability, a European perspective (Grosjean) (Box 50, Folder 1-5)
  - Special issue: Climate change in the 16th century (Pfister) (Box 50, Folder 6-17)
  - Special issue: Climate change in the 16th century (Pfister) (Box 51, Folder 1-2)
  - Special issue: Climate in the Americas, 2005 (Box 51, Folder 3-18)
  - Special issue: Climate extremes (Karl), 1997 (Box 51, Folder 19-23)
  - Special issue: Climate extremes (Karl), 1997 (Box 52, Folder 1-13)
  - Special issue: Global warming and long-term risk (Oppenheimer), 2006 (Box 52, Folder 14-26)
  - Special issue: Climatology of the world's oceans, (Garcia-Herrera), 1750-1850 (Box 53, Folder 1-11)
  - Special issue: Temperature and pressure (Box 53, Folder 12-23)
  - Special issue: Temperature and pressure (Box 54, Folder 1-2)
  - Special issue: Thresholds and response functions (Toth) (Box 54, Folder 3-16)
  - Special issue: AGCI proceedings (Harrey) (Box 54, Folder 17-24)
  - Special issue: AGCI proceedings (Harrey) (Box 55, Folder 1-3)
  - Special issue: Effects of climate change on water (Pennell/Barnett) (Box 55, Folder 4-19)
  - Special issue: Effects of climate change on water (Pennell/Barnett) (Box 56, Folder 1-2)
  - Special issue (Box 56, Folder 3-19)
  - Special issue (Box 57, Folder 1-3)
  - Manuscripts in revision, 2000 (Box 57, Folder 4-16)
  - Manuscripts in revision, 2001 (Box 57, Folder 17-22)
  - Manuscripts in revision, 2001 (Box 58, Folder 1-13)
  - Manuscripts in revision, 2002 (Box 58, Folder 14-25)
  - Manuscripts in revision, 2002 (Box 59, Folder 1-4)
  - Manuscripts in revision, 2005 (Box 59, Folder 5-26)
  - Manuscripts in revision, 2005 (Box 60)
  - [Manuscripts returned to authors for revision] (Box 61)
  - Inactive manuscripts, 1994-1998 (Box 62, Folder 1-24)
  - Rejected manuscripts, A-G, 1999-2003 (Box 62, Folder 25-32)
  - Rejected manuscripts, A-G, 1999-2003 (Box 63, Folder 1-15)
  - Rejected manuscripts, H-R, 1999-2003 (Box 63, Folder 16-29)
  - Rejected manuscripts, H-R, 1999-2003 (Box 64, Folder 1-13)
  - Rejected manuscripts, S-Z, 1999-2003 (Box 64, Folder 14-37)
  - Rejected manuscripts, 1998-2000 (Box 65, Folder 1-20)
  - Rejected manuscripts, 2002-2004 (Box 65, Folder 21-28)
  - Rejected manuscripts, 2002-2004 (Box 66, Folder 1-14)
  - Rejected manuscripts, A-M, 2003-2005 (Box 66, Folder 15-34)
  - Rejected manuscripts, A-M, 2003-2005 (Box 67, Folder 1-7)
  - Rejected manuscripts, N-Z, 2003-2005 (Box 67, Folder 8-29)
  - [Manuscripts; status not indicated] (Box 68)
  - Editorial comments and controversial (Box 69)
  - Editorial comments and controversial (Box 70, Folder 1-12)
  - Administrative files (Box 70, Folder 13-24)
  - Administrative files (Box 71)
  - Special Issue: Abrupt Climate Change near the Poles (Tol Toth Yohe), 2005 (Box 208, Folder 1-24)
- Personal Material, 1966; Series 2